netzerosearch.net 2011-12-15

# NetZero - Value-priced Internet Service Provider - ISP - Free, low-cost and HiSpeed Internet Access. - Privacy and Security

I. Overview.

NetZero is committed to safeguarding your privacy online. NetZero created this Privacy Policy (the " _Policy_ ") in order to demonstrate its firm commitment to protecting the privacy of the users of NetZero products and services (the " _Services_ ") and available through NetZero's websites (the " _Sites_ "). Please read through the information below and any supplemental information referenced in this Policy for additional details about our particular Sites.

This Policy discloses how we use and share your information collected through the use of the Services and the Sites. We use the Information that we collect about you to create a more personalized online experience for you.

If you have a question about any of the information in this Policy, please contact NetZero at: 

Attn: Legal Department   
NetZero, Inc.   
21301 Burbank Boulevard, Woodland Hills, CA 91367   
(818) 287-3000   
privacy@netzero.com

II. What information do we collect from you?

In order to provide Services and maintain our Sites, NetZero collects two types of information from its users and visitors: personal information and non-personal information. Our primary goal in collecting these types of information from you is to provide you with a customized experience while using the Services on our Sites - not to raise concerns about the safety and security of your information.

  1. **Personal information**. Depending on the Service, we may collect personal information (including, but not limited to your name, address, ZIP code, country, phone number and e-mail address), demographic information (including, but not limited to your age, household size, income level, education, gender, information about your business and birth date), financial information (including, but not limited to your credit card information) and psychographic information (including, but not limited to your reason for Internet use, reason for use of the Services and the Sites and topics of interest to you). 
  2. **Non-personal information**. This refers to information that by itself cannot be linked to your personal identity (such as your NetZero member number). We automatically gather certain non-personal information about you based upon your activity on the Sites or the way you use our Services. We also collect machine data (such as processor type and speed, account information, operating system type, internet connection speed, browser type, audio devices, modem devices, video cards and any software on your computer that may interact or interfere with our software or Services) and your web browsing information (such as a web Sites' Uniform Resource Locator (" _URL_ ") that you just came from, which URL you next go to, access times on a URL, certain non-identifying purchase transaction details and the Internet Protocol (" _IP_ ") address from which you have accessed the Sites). 

III. Where do we collect your information?

  1. **Registration and online forms**. We collect information that you submit on registration forms, surveys, questionnaires, responses to sweepstakes or other special offers, or other online forms or interactive portions of our Sites. We may also collect information from users and visitors to our Sites regarding the referring URL, IP address, which browser a person used to come to the Sites and the pages of our Sites that a user or visitor viewed during one's visit. 
  2. **Third-party sources**. We may gather new information or update existing information from other sources including, but not limited to, for example, verifying and updating your address using third-party services, using various methods to update your credit card expiration date or collecting or comparing information from our subsidiaries. 
  3. **Online surveys**. When you participate in an online survey sponsored by a NetZero entity or a trusted partner, we may ask you for certain information, for example, demographic information (like your ZIP code, age or income level) and your hobbies and interests in order to track responses. 
  4. **Contests and Sweepstakes**. We may run contests, sweepstakes and other promotions on our Sites or through our Services, in which we may request entrants to provide personal and/or contact information. NetZero uses the information collected in the entry form to verify the entrant's identity, age and to communicate with entrants. We will not knowingly permit children under the age of 13 to participate in contests or sweepstakes. We may also co-sponsor a contest or sweepstakes with a trusted partner contractually obligated to protect your personal information with whom we will share information obtained as a result of participation in the contest or sweepstakes. 
  5. **Technical/Support Information**. If you contact us by e-mail or other means for technical support or information related to the Service, we may keep a record of your communication and its resolution. Thus, if you report a problem with our Services or Sites, we may collect such Information in a file specific to you. Moreover, if you contact us through our feedback area, we require your name and e-mail address in order to send you a reply. Additionally, if other users or third parties send us correspondence about your activities or postings on our Sites, we may keep the Information in a file specific to you and/or the investigation and action we take. 

IV. How is your information used?

NetZero uses the Information it collects to provide you with more relevant services, including, online shopping, third-party offers, contests, promotions, surveys and advertising. To accomplish this we may collect and perform research on the Information from our users and other parties that provide similar types of consumer information. This research is compiled, analyzed and used to better serve our users, third-party advertisers, and trusted partners. In particular, we have described below some of the ways we use the Information you provide: 

  1. **Personalize your experience**. Information is used to tailor your experience of our Services on the Sites, such as by displaying advertisements and content that might be of interest to you. 
  2. **Respond to inquiries**. If you request information from us, then we will collect Information from you in order to respond to your requests or inquiries. 
  3. **Understand user needs and trends**. We use Information to do internal research on our users' demographics, interests and behavior to better understand and serve our users and visitors. We also collect Information regarding the referring URL, your IP address, which browser you used to come to the Sites and the pages of our Sites that you viewed during your visit. 
  4. **E-mail and direct mail marketing**. You may agree to receive e-mail, advertisements and promotions from us, third-party advertisers, and trusted partners regarding products or services we believe you may be interested in, new features or products we are introducing, tips on product use, and promotions. If you later decide that you wish to cease receiving such e-mail or direct mail marketing, you may do so at any time by opting-out of participation in these marketing activities. 

Since it is necessary for us to contact you regarding certain matters, you may not opt-out of receiving messages related to material company announcements or policy changes, or administrative matters relating to your account, like billing, collections, customer service or the like. 

If you subscribe to a free or discounted version of a Service, you acknowledge that as a condition of receiving such free or discounted Service, you may be required to receive information and advertising related to products and services offered by NetZero. You further acknowledge that any such advertisements and information may be an inseparable part of the free or discounted Service, and in order to opt-out of receipt you may be required to terminate the relevant Service. 

  5. **Diagnose service problems**. We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our Services, servers, software, and to administer our Sites. We also review "log-file" data to monitor Sites performance and analyze traffic and usage patters of our Sites. 

V. Do we monitor your online communications?

We will not intentionally monitor or disclose any private e-mail messages or online communication between you and a third party, although we reserve the right to monitor accounts that we believe, in our sole discretion, to be acting in violation of the Terms of Service or any applicable law or regulation; to protect the integrity of our Services or the Internet community as a whole; in an emergency situation; or pursuant to request of governmental or legal authority.

VI. Who is collecting your information?

NetZero takes great care to ensure our users' privacy-but not every company has comparable policies. While you are on the Sites or utilizing our Services we will be collecting Information, unless it is specifically stated otherwise. Some of our Services are offered in conjunction with third-party advertisers or our trusted partners in a co-branded manner. When we offer you co-branded services or products and you respond with your information, we may share your personal information with our third-party co-branding partner. 

Once you leave our Sites, we cannot assume any responsibility for any other content or practices of unaffiliated sites. Providers of unaffiliated Internet sites or services have separate data and privacy practices independent of our Policy that govern the manner in which they use the information that you provide to them. Even within our Sites, many of the features and much of the content is supplied by third parties (or jointly by NetZero and one or more third-party advertisers or trusted partners), each of which has its own privacy policies and practices, and the Sites may link to some pages provided by third-parties that are co-branded by us and the provider.

VII. With whom do we share your information?

Except as otherwise described in this Policy, we will not disclose or share your unaggregated personal information to an unaffiliated third party unless you consent to the disclosure of such information.

  1. **Sale or rent of personal information**. We do not rent or sell your unaggregated personal information to anyone without your express consent. 
  2. **Our service providers**. Like many companies, we work with service providers who provide services to us. We may share your information with these service providers in order for them to provide their services on our behalf, such as administering surveys, promotions, conducting data processing or analysis, or providing advertising on our Sites. We require each service provider to use the information only as is necessary for the service provider to complete its responsibilities for us, to have in place a privacy policy similar to this Policy and abide by confidentiality restrictions and implement security measures to safeguard such information. 
  3. **Affiliates**. NetZero is a subsidiary of United Online, Inc., which is also the parent company of other entities that offer Internet-related services ("NetZero's Affiliates"). NetZero's Affiliates also have similar privacy policies that protect personal information. NetZero is constantly looking for ways to streamline its technical and administrative processes and offer robust products and services to its subscribers. To this end, NetZero may share your personal information with its Affiliates. 
  4. **Purchasers of the business**. If NetZero sells, assigns or transfers the part of its business that provides a particular service to you, your information may be sold, assigned or transferred as a part of such transaction. 
  5. **Legal Matters; Protection of Rights, Property and Interests; Safety**. 

We may, without your consent, access and disclose your personal information, any communications sent or received by you, and any other information that we have about you or your account: as may be permitted or required by law, regulation, rule or court order; pursuant to requests from governmental, regulatory or administrative agencies or law enforcement authorities; to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims; or to prevent, investigate, identify persons or organizations potentially involved in, or take any action regarding, suspected fraud, violations of our Terms of Service, or activity that appears to us to be illegal or may expose us to legal liability. Additionally, we may disclose your personal information in situations that we believe to be emergencies involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person or property if we believe that your personal information in any way relates to that threat.

VIII. How may you access or update your information?

The information you provide during registration for, or during your use of, the Services is placed in your Personal Profile. You may access or update the information contained in your Personal Profile on the Sites at any time or through other methods provided through our Services. NetZero may update the information in your Personal Profile with information obtained through generally accepted methods of address verification.

IX. How do we protect your information?

NetZero uses security systems and secure computers to protect your information. For example, the information in your Personal Profile is password-protected so that only you may access or change the information. You should not share your password with anyone. NetZero personnel will never ask you to divulge your password in written or electronic communications. We will only ask you for your password when you contact us and only in cases where you request customer service to correct a service problem which requires your password. Additionally, when highly confidential information, such as a credit card number, is transmitted through our websites, it is encrypted by using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) software. Please be aware that Internet security technology changes rapidly and data transmission is never 100% secure. We cannot guarantee that any safeguards we use will completely protect your information from security threats whether now or in the future. You should also be aware that despite our efforts, factors beyond our control may result in disclosure of your information. Accordingly, we are not able to guarantee the security of the information you transmit when utilizing our Services.

X. A note about international users.

The information we collect from users is processed and maintained in the United States, where privacy laws may not be as protective as in your home country. If you are using our Sites from outside of the United States, by providing information to us you are consenting to the transfer of the information to the United States for processing in a manner consistent with this Policy.

XI. A note about the privacy of children ages 13 to 18.

We collect, use, and disclose information about children ages 13 to 18 in the same manner as we do for adults. We believe that it is especially important to protect childrens' privacy online and encourage parents and guardians to spend time online with their children to participate and monitor their Internet activity. If you are under 18, we recommend you get your parents' permission before disclosing any information about yourself to anyone on the Internet. We do not filter advertisements or other content that children may receive, and they could receive content and materials from the Internet and/or advertising that are inappropriate for children.

**_Clickhere for a special notice to the parents of children under 13. _**

XII. Use of cookies and web beacons.

A cookie is a small piece of data that is stored in a browser-related file on your computer's hard drive when you use the Services on the Sites. Cookies are uniquely assigned to your computer, and are read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. Our primary use of cookies is to enable us to recognize your computer each time you return to our Sites or use our Service, keep track of your preferences, determine what you have already seen on our Sites and to improve your online experience. For example, storing a cookie on your computer allows you to login without typing your registered e-mail address or registration number and password. We may also use an e-mail delivery and marketing company to send e-mails that you have agreed to receive. Pixel tags and cookies are used in those e-mail messages to help us measure the effectiveness of our advertising. Third parties, including third-party advertisers, may also set cookies. Such third parties are responsible for placing and using such cookies and may collect information about you through such cookies. We do not have access to such cookies, control the use of such cookies or have control over the privacy policies of such parties. Please also note that certain types of e-mails available through the Services on our Sites may automatically log you into the Sites and/or set new cookies when you click on the links in the e-mails and that you may need to manually remove such cookies if you do not want them to be set on your computer. 

If you do not want cookies stored on your computer you can reject cookies by modifying your web browser setting accordingly (each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences). However, if you choose to reject cookies, you may not be able to access products and services that we offer that require you to "login" or "sign in."

XIII. Preference Advertising.

NetZero may use information such as the websites you visit or online searches that you conduct to deliver or facilitate the delivery of advertisements tailored to your interests. NetZero may also partner with third party advertising companies that serve tailored advertisements. If you would like to learn more about preference advertising and your ability to opt-out from receiving such advertising from third party advertising companies click here.

XIV. Privacy Policy changes.

If NetZero changes its privacy practices as described in this Policy, those changes will be posted in this document so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information and to whom we will disclose it. We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, amend and/or remove portions of this Policy at any time. We will notify you about significant changes in the way we treat your information by sending a notice to the primary e-mail address specified in your account or by placing a prominent notice on the Sites for a period of at least 30 days prior to the Policy change noting that there will be significant changes to this Policy. Please be sure to check this page periodically for changes to our privacy practices.

XV. Acceptance of these terms.

This Policy is incorporated into and subject to the terms of the NetZero Terms of Service. Each time that you use the Sites or our Services, you signify that you have read, understood and agree to be bound by the Terms of Service, which incorporates this Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Policy, you must discontinue using the Services and software, terminate your account and uninstall any copies of software allowing making use of the Sites or our Services possible. 

This Policy is effective upon acceptance in registration for new users, and is otherwise effective on December 31, 2008 for all NetZero users.
